A Guide to the Thomas Jefferson Correspondence, 1810-1817
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Thomas Jefferson Correspondence, 1810-1817
The Library of Virginia
22085
28 leaves and 4 pages, positive and negative photostats
Thomas Jefferson
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Virginius Dabney, 1943.
Biographical Information
Thomas Jefferson was born 13 April 1743 in Goochland County, Virginia (now part of Albemarle County, Virginia). He graduated from the College of William and Mary in 1762. A member of the Virginia House of Burgesses from 1769 to 1775, Jefferson represented Virginia in the Continental Congress in 1775 and 1776. He wrote the Declaration of Independence in 1776. Jefferson served as governor of Virginia from 1779 to 1781. After serving another term in Congress from 1783 to 1784, he was appointed minister to France and served from 1784 to 1788. Jefferson served as Secretary of State under President George Washington from 1789 to 1793, and as Vice President under President John Adams from 1797 to 1801. Jefferson succeeded Adams as president, serving from 1801 to 1809. Upon his retirement, Jefferson returned to his home, Monticello, in Albemarle County. He founded the University of Virginia in Charlottesville, Virginia. Jefferson died 4 July 1826 and was buried at Monticello.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, 1810-1817, of Thomas Jefferson (1743-1826) with George Jefferson (d. 1812) and Patrick Gibson (d. 1827) of Richmond, Virginia, concerning business matters, including Jefferson's finances, building materials, his shipments of flour and tobacco, and George Jefferson's appointment as consul to Lisbon, Portugal.
Contents List
- Letter, 17 January 1810, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, Albemarle County, Virginia, to Gibson and Jefferson, Richmond, Virginia, concerning a draw upon his account.
- Letter, 16 March 1810, from George Jefferson, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson concerning a draft on Thomas Jefferson's account.
- Letter, 19 March 1810, from George Jefferson, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson cerning money for a bill and the arrival of some plaister of paris for Thomas Jefferson.
- Letter, 28 September 1810, from George Jefferson, Richmond, to Thomas Jefferson stating that window glass has arrived for Thomas Jefferson.
- Letter, 11 March 1811, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to George Jefferson, Richmond, stating that Patrick Gibson should not go to Lisbon, Portugal for political reasons.
- Letter, 11 March 1811, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to George Jefferson, Richmond, congratulating him on being appointed consul to Lisbon, Portugal.
- Letter, 6 October 1815, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning the late payment of a debt.
- Letter, 20 October 1815, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning his personal finances.
- Letter, 28 October 1815, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning his finances and his flour and tobacco.
- Letter, 27 January 1816, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, regarding drafts on Jefferson for Thomas Jefferson Randolph.
- Letter, 15 May 1816, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning sale of flour and financial matters.
- Letter, 1 July 1817, from Thomas Jefferson, Poplar Forest, Bedford County, Virginia, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning the signing of notes.
- Letter, 26[?] October 1817, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, regarding the shipping of his flour and financial matters.
- Letter, 30 October 1817, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning outstanding notes and flour.
- Letter, 15 November 1817, from Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, to Patrick Gibson, Richmond, concerning the shipment of items.